LANDON MORGAN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

PHONE: 615-307-0005
EMAIL: MORGANLANDON@GMAIL.COM
WEBSITE: <u>IANDONMORGAN.GITHUB.IO</u>

GITHUB: GITHUB.COM/IANDONMORGAN/LINKEDIN: LINKEDIN.COM/IN/LANDOLAKE/

ABOUT ME

My professional background is primarily in video production and live tv entertainment. Since the mid-1990's, I proactively sought codecentered side hustles. My first experiences with programming languages were seeing C++ and coding in HTML when I was 15. The site my friend Luke and I created was featured in USA Today.

I created nashvillePA.com in 2007 to get my friends and production assistants in Nashville their next gig. In 2010 I was commissioned to build holyvintage.com, a retail site managing an inventory of vintage t-shirts with only my knowledge of HTML. I am greatly enjoying my recommitment to learn code since becoming a full-time Software Developer in 2019.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Manager, Video Content Production

Sony Music Entertainment | Aug 2017 - Dec 2019

- Designed and maintained intake form to process the workflow of project requests from other departments.
- Liaised with all departments for video content needs.
- Researched and targeted top creatives in Nashville and commissioned video work to independent contractors, sustaining a 20% network growth (active freelancers).
- Found, recommended, trained, and mentored the person who later applied for and was promoted to manager following my departure.
- Communicated status and updates to artists and management teams through regularly scheduled meetings, or during projects.

Talent Supervisor (Live TV Events)

One Foot Productions | Aug 2014 - Aug 2017

- Led team of liaisons to manage the logistics related to participating and performing artists, and the artists' band, crew, management and label teams for large scale live tv events.
- Supervised core team of approximately 30 people, with up-to an additional 100-150 talent escorts for show day.
- Worked with project manager to communicate logistics team needs to the software developers.
- Annual events worked include Rock and Roll Hall of Fame Induction Ceremony. Nickelodeon HALO Awards. BET Experience, iHeart Radio Music Awards, and more.

Producer (Video Content)

AOL StudioNow | Jan 2011 - Mar 2014

- Personally recruited and onboarded hundreds of freelance video professionals into the AOL StudioNow network.
- Produced projects inside top tier advertising agencies.
- Traveled Internationally (produced projects in France and London)
- Salesforce admin certified (currently inactive/expired).

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Event Volunteer, PyTn 2020

Assisted speakers with AV for their slides, and timed presentations.

Creative Production Volunteer, Cross Point Church

Served as booth and broadcast director, technical director, camera operator, and various roles as needed since 2006.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Software Developer

Nashville Software School | Nov 2019 - Present

Full-stack bootcamp focused on Python/Django, and front-end languages including JavaScript, React, CSS3, and HTML5.

- Gained knowledge through teamwork and group projects.
- Practiced Scrum Agile methodology, sprints, and daily stand-ups.
- Technologies learned through bootcamp curriculum include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, JSON, JSON-server for API fetch/data storage, GitHub, Python, and SQL.
- Learned remotely, and worked on teams remotely from March 2020 and June 2020.
- Workflow for projects included creation of Entity Relationship Diagrams through dbdiagram.com and sketchboard.me.
- Mentored students as "little siblings" enrolled in the cohort six weeks behind in curriculum.

RECENT PROJECTS

Front-end capstone project: 'Commissioner Mordan'

- Written with React.js library using hooks, state, props, and routes to solve problems related to the sharing of information and managing projects on behalf of artists.
- Target user group for this web application is a record label or production company.
- Styling with CSS, Semantic UI, and React-bootstrap for navigational bar.
- Additional technologies incorporated include react-currencyinput for handling budget amounts. React-PopUp and React Confirm Alert incorporated for modals and alerts, and React Router utilized for route handling.

Back-end Python group project: Keahua Arboretum

- Python command line application and group learning exercise; my role included "unofficial project manager" for our group.
- Used classes and multiple inheritance for reusability of code and management of class object properties.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Web and Software Development Certificate

Nov 2019 - June 2020

Cohort with emphasis on Python, Django.

University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK

Bachelor of Business Administration, Marketing Aug 1999 - Aug 2003

Aug 1999 - Aug 2003

Activities and Societies: Campus Activities Council (CAC) Public Relations Chair, CAC Film Series Chair, Vice-President Kappa Alpha Order, Honors Dorm Resident Advisor

Vancouver Film School, Vancouver, BC

Certification, Film Production

Aug 2003 - Aug 2004

Graduated with honours

臺灣大學 National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan Mandarin Chinese Level 1

Feb 2002 - May 2002

Graduated in 90th percentile. One of the first two students to establish the foreign exchange between the University of Oklahoma and National Taiwan University.